So then it's going to set it to another
payload. And so you can like, oh wow, we
just found a vulnerability in Kaido.
That's really funny and really cool.
This will definitely be fixed by the
time it goes live. But that's hilarious.
I'm actually going to send that right
now to the team.
>> Best part of when you can just, you
know, critical think.
[Music]
Hello.
>> Yeah,
>> dude.
[Music]
All right, hackers. Here's the deal.
Before you skip forward, give me like
two seconds to give you a takeaway.
Okay, here it is. Threat Locker Detect
is the best EDR around. They have a ton
of tool integrations. The alerts are
high signal, so you're not swimming in a
bunch of garbage. And both alerting and
remediation actions are super
customizable. It's definitely the one
you want. Okay, that's it. Skip forward
if you must, but I do feel like you
should know why I think that, right?
Well, we've talked a lot about the
threat locker suite, and frankly,
they're the best implemented tools
around from a technical perspective.
With this EDR, they're focusing a lot on
customization and high signal stuff like
PowerShell activity, log deletion,
sketchy RDP sessions, stuff that I have
wished many times EDRs were not uh
detecting actively. Okay. Um, and while
it does work out of the box, it also
gives you, the experienced purple
teamer, the tools you need to implement
custom logic to lock hackers out of your
network at the first sign of trouble.
That trouble is the trouble that you are
most qualified to recognize. So, they're
equipping you to to deal with it right
away. Um, the definitely the ones you
guys want to go with if you're looking
for a new EDR tool. All right, that's
it. Let's go back to the show.
Sup hackers. Got the this weekend bug
bounty segment for you. First up is this
uh Nulcon Berlin live hacking event that
is being run by Yes WeHack. Uh this is
just around the corner September 4th
through 5th and uh it seems like a
really great opportunity. The way that
Yes We Hack runs these live hacking
events is they reveal the target the day
of. I do have a little piece of insight
that it is a big company known all over
the world. Um so and it's open to all
ncon participants. So if you're hitting
that up in Germany then definitely check
out the live hacking event with Yes, We
Hack. Um, next is also something from
Yes, we hack. Uh, the bug bounty
bulletin, which is something that I
wasn't really on my radar until just a
week ago. Uh, but apparently it's like
pretty big. It's got like 17,000
subscribers on LinkedIn and it is Yes,
We Hacks sort of weekly newsletter. Um,
got some great content in there. Oh,
what is this? Is this Oh, is this
critical thinking? Oh, how did that get
in there? So funny. Um, no, but this is
another great place to uh get news on on
Book Bounty stuff. So certainly check it
out. Um they they talk about Kaido uh
new Kaido video, another live hack
event. Yes, we hack ran. Um it's looking
like a good roundup. All right, last but
not least, we've got Grab with Hacker 1.
Um Grab has been running their program
for 10 years. Uh and as a result,
they're doing an anniversary promotion,
which is a 2x bounty multiplier from
August 11th to September 10th. Okay, so
definitely going to want to check that
out. Uh, also just check out the stats
for this program. Three hours to first
response, three days to triage, six days
to bounty. That is like S tier response
time, and they're doubling their
bounties, and they've got a massive
scope. So, uh, this is looking like an
amazing program that I've been sleeping
on. You guys should definitely check it
out, too. All right, that's it for the
This Week in Bug Bounty. Let's get back
to the show.
>> Hey guys, welcome back to the Critical
Thinking podcast. um Joseph Freso this
time and I'm interviewing the great Jack
Cable and I'll get into his intro in a
minute but first we'll kick it off with
a bug of course. So Jack um you just
teased it to me and I'm pretty excited
about it. So what bug did you bring for
us today?
>> Awesome. Well well first of all thank
you so much for having me. Great to to
be on the the podcast.
>> So so the one that I've got for today is
a fun one, right? Um so um that this
relates to Clo uh- which I imagine that
uh people u might be familiar with. You
know they they've gotten a decent amount
of attention lately. Um and this was
maybe a month or so ago. I was u poking
around on their desktop app. Uh found a
number of things which we can probably
get into to later um around um
understanding their their system prompt
things like that. But the the
interesting bug was I was looking into
um essentially seeing if there were were
ways to compromise the the desktop
application. Um and I saw a few things,
right? Because it's an Electron app. Um
and they were loading in basically, you
know, it essentially takes a screenshot
of your computer, sends it off to to
their server, which sends it to OpenAI
or Enthropic.
um and it it kind of renders the the
response uh from
their server as markdown. Um so so that
got me interested, right? Um and of
course um with with Electron apps um
since they're just you know websites
basically if you can get cross-ite
scripting um that that that can be
pretty severe. And um the the
interesting thing here is that um I I
noticed one they weren't using the
Electron sandbox. Um and two um kind of
I noticed that if you were able to say
get a link to be displayed and then the
user clicks that opens it up. Um it
turns out they were passing quite a bit
of uh context to that new website. Um
and in particular there were a number of
uh post message um handlers available
that would essentially um receive um
messages
uh right from the application. I think
this is probably um intended for like
internally right because they want to do
things like take screenshots or update
different permissions. Um, but what I
don't think they anticipated was that
any website that was opened in clearly
could access this and in particular
probably the the most dangerous one
right was the they had a function to
take a screenshot. So I tested that out
and takes a screenshot of your screen
unsurprisingly but that's pretty bad to
give any arbitrary website the ability
to do. Um, so essentially, right, I I
rigged up a PC where I just continually
took a screenshot of um the person's
computer. Um, so effectively you're now
recording their their screen and and all
they have to do is um click a link. Um,
so what should have done is given that
to Amazon. So when anyone was using
Cleia and interviews, it was actually
monitoring the interview e screen,
right? It's like it's like a reverse.
They think they're getting away with
cheating on the uh interview, but
actually Amazon's just monitoring their
screen the whole time.
>> Yeah. Yeah, exactly. You're you're the
one who who's being recorded instead.
So, um So, yeah, that was a fun one. Um
I disclosed it to them. They did uh fix
it uh quickly.
>> Did any of the post message allow for
XSS? Cuz where it's an Electron app,
that could have just been RC, right?
>> So, so yeah, I was also looking for X S
I can't talk. XSS or um things like
whether kind of input from that would go
into a system command. Uh beyond that
there there wasn't a ton of attack
service. There were um functions for
instance like request microphone access
things like that but nothing that
necessarily took in input um and that
yeah
>> but still I mean pretty bad screenshots
of the of the desktop is basically
leaking any secrets and anything else.
So that's cool.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Exactly. Sweet, dude. Good
find. Well, I will now intro you um
since you're appropriately christened
here. Um yeah, so for anybody who
doesn't know who Jack Cable is, he was a
very top bug hunter. I think he has like
10,000 rep on Hacker 1 and um was kind
of around the live hacking scene and
stuff for a little bit, but has since uh
started a company called Corridor. Did
you do anything in between those two
things? Like was that did you have any
like uh do you have a company before
Corridor? So, so I was actually working
in government uh before this and that
was a lot of the reason, you know, that
I um stopped doing bug bounty as much
because as it turns out when you're
working in government, you you can't
really get income from um outside
sources. Um, so spent a couple years was
um working in the um Senate for one year
writing um legislation around um things
like open source software security and
then what was at um CISA cyber security
and infrastructure security agency for
for two years uh leading on the the
secure by design initiative. So so did a
lot to try to get tech companies to to
improve that their software security.
>> Yeah. Yeah. That's awesome. Did did
being involved deeper than any of the
rest of us are make you more hopeful or
kind of like uh less hopeful for
positive change in in that way? Like do
you think that being a part of
government and then also even more than
just being a part of like you know a
specific agency but like also just being
involved in the legislation process. Was
that like disheartening or was it
actually like not that bad?
Um so so I think there there's some of
both right where the the time I was um
in the Senate for instance uh was a very
productive time kind of around cyber
security legislation there there was a
lot of bipartisan support that there
still is some today but but um maybe a
little less so um and so so saw a lot of
positive momentum um and likewise being
at SISA found that when you're in the
the right place and government kind of
went when appropriately empowered
there's a lot that can be done. Um so so
did a bunch of work to um get
commitments from from companies for
instance to improve their their product
security. One of the elements for
instance this was the the secure by
design pledge was to um operate a
vulnerability disclosure policy. Um so
so um tried to really kind of strengthen
the role of security research. Um so I
think there are opportunities to to have
um some large scale impact here. Of
course change doesn't happen overnight.
Uh but but I do think it's important for
for you know um technical people to to
be in the room because ultimately
>> Oh yeah 100%.
>> Yeah. You need to to understand how
things work under the hood.
>> What is that like VDP or VR or VRP thing
that Casey Ellis kind of started? Did um
disclosed.io.
>> Yeah. Was that uh at all like an
inspiration or useful to you guys in
that whole
>> Certainly.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So So I I got involved with
with Disclos.io
um a while ago when was starting out.
Um, and I I think definitely a lot of
that that momentum kind of helped to to
underpin a lot a lot of the work that
got done where, you know, now we're in a
point where it is really the the norm to
operate a vulnerability disclosure
policy, right? That's sort of the bare
minimum for a company who wants to be
responsible around security. Of course,
even better to to go incentivize
research with a bug bounty. Um, but at
the the baseline, you you need to have a
way to to take in reports from hackers.
And yeah, a lot of the the work that
that Casey Knight did as well was around
advocating for legal safe harbor to uh
get give these asurances that a company
won't u take u legal action against you.
Um so so so that work what was really
essential and um yeah a lot of what I
focused on in government right was kind
of helping to to continue to to make
this the the norm um and make the
expectation that that companies would um
like that that's in the pledge language
is also to have safe harbor within their
vulnerability disclosure policy um to
>> basically reduce friction there to
deploy it a lot like easier or cuz no
company's going to do it if it's a heavy
lift to actually like you put those
terms and those agreement out there. But
if it's like a oneclick or like here,
just put this on your website, then all
of a sudden it becomes really feasible,
right?
>> Exactly. Exactly.
>> Cool. Well, one thing I wanted to do was
like talk kind of practically about AI
stuff, obviously. Um, it's kind of what
people expect me to talk about, but it's
also what I love and I find enjoyable.
So, what at what point, well, I guess
kind of two things. One, I was going to
see when it when did it click for you or
when did like what kind of opened your
eyes or made you find kind of AI apps
more interesting? And then two, like you
know, what have you been doing in that
field or kind of pressing into? And
obviously cordard.dev has a little bit
of of that to say there. But let's start
with that first question. What what
exactly got you where you're like, wow,
what was the eye opening kind of moment
for the mixture of AI and security,
whether it's from the offensive side of
things or the defensive side of things?
>> Yeah. Yeah. I mean, for me it was really
twofold. So, so one um and through the
course of the the work at CISA, right,
as well as uh ju just my time doing bug
bounties saw kind just how much
companies were struggling with product
security and as you know right often
it's the very basic vulnerabilities that
slip through and cause a lot of impact
cause a lot of harm. Um and kind just
got me thinking okay there has to be a
better way. Um, and then really what
what I think kind of ma made me realize
there's a lot lot of opportunity here
was just using the these tools for
development. So using cursor um quad
code some other tools and seeing kind of
just how capable they are. Um, of course
they're they're they they all have their
limitations, but like as a software
developer, these tools have helped me
work, you know, five 10 times as fast
and if I try to, you know, go code
something without um won't these tools
now I'm just going to be so much slower.
Um so so it kind of got me thinking okay
if AI is this good at understanding code
writing code um it it must be quite
capable as well around um aspects like
vulnerability discovery as well as other
workflows within um application
security. Um so that was kind of the
starting point. Yeah
>> I made that same leap in my head but I
don't know that was intuitively true or
like I don't know if it was intuitive to
everyone else when that first kind of
popped off. Right. like it makes
complete sense. But it is kind of
interesting how like the theory of mind
works for uh humans versus like like
people who are familiar and intimate
kind of with like LLMs today and what
they're expecting that other LLMs would
be capable of. even just like the theory
of mind of a brain that's working off of
tokens instead of like our brains which
can see both words or characters and can
like parse them both independently and
uniquely and how LLM's kind of parse
things via tokens and like being able to
have theor theory of mind for what the
AI might see with like how it's viewing
the world in tokens instead of viewing
it with characters versus words is like
very interesting to me and so I think
that's kind of like a similar thing you
did there where you basically understood
that hey if this thing's good at
development it's also processed all the
PRs and all the security fixes across
all of GitHub as well. So, it probably
also knows what vulnerabilities look
like and how to exploit them and that
sort of thing. Um, yeah. So, that's
cool. And so, then like what what
exactly are you all building with
corridor.dev?
>> Yeah. So, so really the focus with
corridor, right, is building um kind of
applying AI to help um product security
teams. Um, and I'd say it's really a
full range of of the the work that they
do. So, so it's both around kind of
better enabling vulnerability discovery
um and really building up the the kind
of context of a codebase uh but but then
it's tying this into kind of every stage
of the the development process. Um so so
we talked to product security teams who
almost you know universally are are
overwhelmed. They have too much work to
do. Um their existing like stack
analysis tools are surfacing I don't
know like 90% plus false positives. They
don't have time to go through those.
developers don't have time. Um, and
they're also missing the vulnerabilities
that that actually matter. Um, so so
what we're focusing on is really
enabling the these proc teams to to
multiply their work just like you know
curse or other tools have totally
changed the game of software
development. But in many ways it feels
like security teams are still living in
the the past with their tooling. Um, so,
so it's around capitalizing on these
advancements to, um, kind of help
product security teams review every pull
request, be able to um, take all the,
you know, bug bounty reports that
they're getting, act on them more
quickly, those sorts of workflows that I
think are really underexplored.
>> Yeah. Yeah. That's awesome. When you
were doing uh, bug bounty, what was kind
of your bread and butter? What type of
vulnerabilities were you like typically
finding more of versus the other ones?
So, so yeah, it was a mix. I think
probably the most interesting most
frequent ones were were were
authorization vulnerabilities. And you
know, some of them can be quite simple
where you just change an ID and it gives
you all sorts of um sensitive
information. Others could be kind of a
little more uh kind of complicated
business logic things. But I think those
were really some of the the more
impactful uh vulnerabilities that I
reported over the years. Um, and there
were some some interesting ones too,
kind of like right when I was getting
into to bug bounties. This was when I
was like 15 or 16. Some of the kind of
initial things I I was looking for were
race conditions. Um, and and did this
especially on like cryptocurrency
websites where it would basically go to
everyone and see, okay, can I like
withdraw money multiple times? Can I um
can do do other actions that would allow
me to um basically
yes um steal money if I want to and
found a number of those vulnerabilities
that I disclosed. There was one exchange
where I think like I could have drained
their wallet of like 100k or something
in Bitcoin if I had wanted to. Um so a
lot of those types of flaws that um you
know might um go missed without more
extensive testing. Yeah, that's
interesting because that was back before
um the BERT plugin for race condition
specific tests, right? Like the last
attack, it was before that. Yeah. Do you
remember how you were doing it?
>> Yeah, I mean I and I I still do this and
work works a good amount of the time.
Basically just um you know doing burp
copy as curl and then opening a terminal
sending off multiple requests in
parallel. Um so I'm sure Yeah. doesn't
all the things that Yeah. Yeah. Exactly.
Yeah. the the burp extension pro
probably has a better detection rate but
at least for a lot of these things where
you know it's not um like instantaneous
operation um it can do do quite well.
Yeah I think I this is like when I was
like 15 I read this blog post of someone
who had done this in like Starbucks or
something and I was like wow I should
really start testing this out and it
worked quite a bit. There's so many cool
little small bug classes like race
conditions or like um the most recent
episode that just aired uh today as
we're recording this uh July 24th. Uh
Justin interviewed Matias and he um it's
all about archive attacks. I don't know
if you if you saw it in your feed yet,
but it's like really neat. It's
basically like a bunch of you know
variations of the old like uh zip slip
attacks, but um you know just new
variations of it and you know obviously
pretty big impact. It's neat the way
there are so many like little tiny
niches. Um, cool. Yeah. So, coming back
to the corded dev thing, one thing that
I thought was interesting was I think
you tweeted or saw about it and that um
Oh, no. It was actually in one of your
congressional speaking things. You're
basically like, you know, AI is going to
write, you know, plenty of
vulnerabilities and I found that to
definitely be true in my kind of vibe
coding in the last few months.
>> But I'm also like, yeah, but so are
plenty of like novice developers, right?
like uh before vibe coding bug bounty
was lucrative because humans write lots
of vulnerabilities and so like it
doesn't change the game too much like
it's like um it's almost independent of
AI writing vulnerabilities that AI prod
would actually be useful right it's like
even if we didn't have vibe coding this
would still be a very high utility tool
>> yeah yeah so so to me what what's really
interesting right is a lot of how I
think about it is in terms of volume and
scale
And we we know that the these AI
development tools are allowing
developers to write code much faster
than ever before, much higher volumes.
We also know that's enabling people who
have never code before to go and you
know v code a website or or something
like that. Um, so I think it does to
your point, um, just continue expanding
the attack surface where where I'm less
worried about, you know, novel
vulnerabilities getting introduced from
a VC code app, but it's more about,
okay, these um, models are going to
introduce the the same types of flaws
that we've known about for decades that
humans haven't been able to root out.
Um, that that are going to continue to
give us problems. Um and I had the the
chance to to uh testify to to Congress.
This was maybe a month or two ago um at
Stanford. Um and a lot of the focus was
around kind of how how AI was affecting
security. One of the things I mentioned
there is there's this benchmark called
backbench which looks at um how well
LLMs do at writing secure code. um and
and and found maybe unsurprisingly that
even the best models about 20 to 30% of
the time uh do introduce vulnerabilities
uh right and they can can can often can
be you know basic things like SQL
injections excess I've had like when
using models myself it's like adds a
command injection vulnerability or
something and if you tell it like okay
write a secure command execution then
it'll
um do it securely but but otherwise it
it won't. Um so so it's things like that
that these models are introducing and
especially when it gets to to things
like business logic flaws. I I think
that's where a lot of the you know
vulnerabilities in in Vive Code apps
that that we'll see will originate. Uh
because again that that requires kind of
the the person who who's behind the
wheel who who's using the these tools to
actually understand the security model.
Um and as we we allow people with with
less and less experience to build these
apps, I think the the kind of yeah
attack surface is just going to kind of
continue to to balloon.
>> Yeah. Same same kind of story there for
you know human like coders or I guess
what I'm trying to think what I'm trying
to say is like you know big companies
with big budgets have had static code
analysis tools for a long time right
it's going to find the places where you
might have code injection or where you
might have um XSS or where you might
have a SQL injection but the business
logic flaws and you know um permission
issues like arback permission issues are
just like never going to be found by
static analysis or probably even like
lots of times from code review because
it just requires the app to actually be
running to test a lot of those things,
right?
>> Um so yeah, that's really interesting.
Uh and I I actually think that the the
very final form there
>> um
will hopefully be eventually be solved
by hackbots, right? Because it really
does need to have like live testing on
top of something like Corridor or what I
don't understand why this hasn't existed
yet. I hope with GitHub releasing GitHub
Spark this week that they'll eventually
release it. But I don't understand why
GitHub doesn't have automatic security
PR reviews. It's just like it's ripe for
the taking. It's right there. I would
pay a subscription for it. Every company
would if like every PR you put out just
had an automated security like like uh
uh wow what's it called? Code review.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Exactly. That
and that's something we we've been doing
and and found that work quite well. Um
and to your point like Yeah. I think um
like especially when it comes to to
authorization type bugs that that's not
something you're going to be able to
find with like stack analysis. It's
something that you need to actually
understand how the the application works
and operates.
>> Um and like you see this a lot with
these like you know zero code vioded
sites. a lot of them use like I don't
know Superbase or Firebase for the
database and have like pretty secure
configurations but the the aspect that
can go wrong right that you can't just
like tell hard code or kind of yeah
prevent by by default I is when it comes
to permissions cuz like with superbase
for instance you need to define
authorization policies for who can
access what um and kind of securely
doing that is not a a trivial problem.
So, so it's it's areas like that that I
think are are really going to be the the
long tale that to your point um AI can
can help us to to understand how an
application works. But um like I think
as you know the if there's I think yeah
you know one law in security that it's
that as the amount of code grows as the
complexity of code grows that the number
of vulnerabilities um increases uh by
quite a bit. So I think we we'll we'll
just see more of that.
>> Yeah. Yeah, and honestly like that's I
had never thought about this before, but
the fact that Vibe coding kind of breaks
down at a certain size is like a good
thing for security right now because
it's still manageable to kind of code
review it and to like find those little
vulnerabilities whenever it can go
slightly longer horizon. Like
>> if you were like to let for example
Gemini 25 Pro output you know a 500,000
token app like the chance of
vulnerabilities is way higher like you
said because the more complexity and the
more code the more likely there are to
be vulnerabilities and so and these
coding systems are going to keep
improving right it's right now it's the
worst they'll ever be as they always say
so as these systems in the next year or
two ramp up to being able to build much
more complex app there's going to be
many more vulnerabilities the other
thing I thought about that you mentioned
on the permissioning thing with
superbase because I do think that's a
big deal is do you know do you know if
Superbase is able to be deployed via
like Terraform in the same way you can
do like GitHub repos um such that you
can manage permissions with like uh
configuration files because like um you
know when you're adding new members to a
new organization and GitHub or whatever
if you've got it all deployed via
Terraform or something you can like
actually manage those permissions in the
file and I think that would make LLMs
much better than them having to use the
UI or UX right of superbase.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Um I think that is
what many of these like vibe coding
tools are doing is that they'll generate
like a kind of um a lot of them are
using superbases like rowle security um
kind of configurations and they do have
a file that contains the essentially
authorization policies uh for your
codebase. Um so so certainly yeah I
think um you know having the these
configuration files is a good thing but
but what really matters is okay the the
contents of them actually um kind of
lining up with with the security model
of the application to your point the the
bigger the um codebase grows the the
more potential for missteps there. I've
noticed that um my apps whenever I'm
letting an LLM develop them often get
insecure when I'm struggling with
something that is usability, which is
kind of funny because it's that tension
between usability and security. Like I
was working on an app where it's
basically just like read only public or
admins.
>> And I wanted the read only public to
basically show the results from like a
bunch of matches.
>> But it it but like the the table kept
getting like 401 or 403 based on the way
it had set up the API to pull those
results to pull to pull those matches.
And then so it's like nah let's just
make this public when actually what it
needed to do was think about like what
data was in that table rather than just
like switching the table to being public
right and so I thought that was like
kind of interesting and probably in a
way that it plays out pretty often.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Exactly. I think there's
>> um yeah a lot of potential like I've
seen this even outside security context
where you know you ask the LM to do
something and it does that as well as
like through other things that you
didn't ask like kind of often they'll
you know be lazy and try to to take
shortcuts instead of actually fixing
that the underlying issue.
>> Yeah. The other thing that I've been
wrestling with is like on the two ends
of the spectrum from like using SDKs and
libraries to just like rolling your own.
I I actually like to kind of roll my
own. Not personally, like when I'm
developing personally, I definitely
don't. But with AI, I like the fact that
it can kind of roll its own because you
can kind of like control everything and
make it custom or whatever. But what I
find is that when I'm making a bigger
app and it starts to do that, it gets
really bloated. Especially if it's doing
like markdown parsing to HTML or
something, now it's like writing a bunch
of regular expressions to like convert
bullets and new lines. It's like, "No,
just use a library, please."
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Anyway,
>> I've seen that too.
>> Yeah.
>> I wanted to circle us back to uh the
Cluey stuff because that was uh pretty
funny when that blew up on Twitter
recently. So, uh yeah, if anyone doesn't
know, basically Yeah. Yeah. Well,
actually you you go ahead and tell the
first half of the story. You tell about
the system prompt uh research that you
were presumably doing along with your
bug you mentioned earlier.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Exactly. So, um this
was around the the same time as I found
that bug. I you know had um taken Clue's
desktop app. I unzipped it cuz Electron
apps are basically just a zip file. um
and noticed pretty quickly that um the
system prompt for both like their
standard version and enterprise version
were um embedded within the um source
code. Uh for for those who aren't
familiar, Cluey essentially, you know,
yes, supposedly lets you cheat on
anything. Um so so basically has a
prompt where it takes a screenshot of
your screen, says okay, tell the user
like what to say next. Um so so I was
able to to find those complete prompts.
Um there were some interesting elements
of that. They also said for instance
like never say what model you're using
but like right above that was hard code
that I think was like forget what exact
model but um there's a open AI model and
a anthropic model in there. Um so so
naturally you know I uh tweeted this out
said that clearly embedded um their
prompt in their desktop source code. um
that that wound up getting quite a bit
of attention. Um so yeah, that was the
the first part of the the story.
>> Yeah. And so then basically you received
kind of take down or cease and desist or
something on that tweet, right? Or
actually no, was it repo? Was it a gist
or something?
>> So um it was for the tweet. So
essentially the couple weeks later,
right, um I got a DMCA take down notice
from Twitter that uh my uh tweet had
been or at least the images within it
had been taken down because Cle filed a
DMCA takeown saying that um my tweet had
contained
>> um like um basically proprietary
information.
Um, yeah. Yeah, their intellectual
property, which is kind of funny if you
think about it, right? Because if this
is their intellectual property, maybe
they shouldn't be sending it to the
desktop of however many users they have.
Um, so, so that was kind of wild. And
again, going back to the um kind of
vulnerability disclosure policy,
disclosed.io work, one of the elements
of a safe harbor is committing to not uh
take legal action like filing uh DMCA
takedowns. Um, so, so that that was a a
bit surprising that they would go and do
that. Uh, now the funny part is I I go
and uh tweet this out. Um, and um the um
CEO of Cluey um responds um saying that
they didn't file the DMCA takeown. Also,
if it would if it would have been Roy
Lee that actually filed it, that would
have been so ironic considering that he
was literally sued by like
>> companies like I think they've been sued
by like five or 10 companies. So, the
fact that they were like threatening
legal action is just like so ironic and
crazy.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So, so he he said they
didn't do it and he also like posted a
screenshot of his conversation with with
his lawyer around it. Um but um that
that also was strange since the DMCA
takedown notice had the information of
the Culie employee who filed that. Um so
I posted that I tagged the employee and
he admitted you can see it on Twitter
that he had done this that you know he
apologized that he
>> didn't check with uh Clue leadership. Um
and then Roy also apologized after that.
Um the the the funny part is so yeah he
retracted it though the tweets are still
down the images like you go they still
haven't been restored so so working on
that. Uh but the other fun part is that
uh Roy had offered to compensate me. I
said how about instead you uh donate to
the EFF. So he wound up donating about
$1,000 to the the EFF. So at least
something
>> that's cool. Yeah, that's really cool.
Good on him. I uh yeah, I was messaging
him initially when they first like kind
of got started and stuff and we were we
were messing a little bit, but I don't
think that he uh likes me too much
anymore. I basically was just like
sharing some other vulnerabilities they
had at the very beginning and uh he was
like, "No, no, no, it's not vulnerable."
And then when it came out, it was super
vulnerable. I was like, "I told you so."
And then he he hated that. So,
>> u but anyways, yeah, that's funny and
cool. And I think that um if anything,
they probably viewed that as like free
media attention with the way that they
run their company. though I don't think
that he is actually bothered by it at
all. Right.
>> Yeah. Um cool. Yeah. So, I do think um
you would maybe be a good person to talk
about this. This is a little bit of a of
a hot take. I personally don't think
that there's a lot of risk these days
for a known bug hunter to hack on things
that they do not have permission to hack
on. and from being on the legislative
side and you know working at CISA and
also being like a reasonable ethical
moral person um I would be interested in
your thoughts on that and I think we
could kind of break this down into two
categories. One is let's say testing
with your own accounts. So I know
because of that like Supreme Court's
recommendation I think testing with your
own accounts is like most people think
that that actually is probably fine or
at least the people that I kind of
talked to about this. And then and then
let's say another situation where like
you don't have two accounts and you
can't get two accounts because it's like
tied to your identity or something and
you still want to vet the application
for your own usage. So it is still well
maybe there's three categories. Uh sorry
to make this confusing. So one is you're
testing an app that you're using and you
have two users and you only test your
users you own. Two is you're testing an
app that you do actually use and you can
claim that you're like actually wanting
to test it for your own usage, for
example, but you don't have a second
account and you want to check for things
like, you know, that would disclose
other people's information like IDOR or
whatever else. And then the third
category we'll say is apps that you
actually don't use and you have no right
to be testing on. So like you're trying
to hack F1 or, you know, you're trying
to hack the NBA, right? Like but they
don't have bug bounty programs or VDPS.
And so I still, you know, I don't do it.
I have a wife and three children and um
you know my risk tolerance is low so I
don't do it but I still talk to people
and I basically tell people that I think
that the the real true risk of
legislation coming if you're willing to
disclose whatever you find responsibly
is basically infinite like approaching
zero these days um especially if you
have a reputation with the with the you
know bug bounty platforms or whatever so
give me your take on those three on
those three things
>> so yeah yeah super interesting topic and
of course I'll start this by saying I'm
not a lawyer. Please um anyone listening
don't take this as legal advice. Um
>> so uh the the current state of things so
one in terms of what is legally okay. Um
is one if you are are testing something
that that you have locally. Um so so for
instance like in this clearly scenario
right this was their desktop application
I was testing on my computer. um in the
the past like uh decades ago companies
would bring you know um kind of legal
action under say DMCA against
researchers saying you you didn't have
the right to reverse engineer that
program. Um we now have um there's a
security research exemption um in the
the DMCA. So if you're doing um good
faith security research
um then um you are allowed to to test um
something locally. Uh now where it does
get a lot fuzzier is when um that that
application isn't you know hosted
yourselves but it's someone else's
application. um and write the main
>> for if it's client side JavaScript are
you like I guess technically allowed to
probably look at that part but you can't
test for server side v or something
>> so if you're reading letter of the law
>> yeah yeah you can essentially you know
reverse engineer the the client side
JavaScript or like desktop application
or if you get I don't know like the
binary of an application or something
like that where it gets fuzzier in the
the US is the so the computer for abuse
act CFAA says essentially any um
unauthorized access to a computer system
is illegal um unless you have permission
um specific permission to test it. Um,
and that's where again, right, having a
VDP or bug bounty program, which
proactively is a company saying, "Hey,
we want you to test this. Here are the
rules that you can follow." Ideally,
they'll have a safe harbor to say, "We
commit to not taking legal action." But
that's the the reason that's so
important, right, is that's providing
authorization for you to go and test a
system. um in the absence of that right
in your examples uh technically anything
that you do could be considered to be
unauthorized access and u violating
CFAA. Um now to your point um like if
you are testing on your own account if
you find something if you responsibly
disclose it um it's unlikely that a
company would choose to take legal
action against you. Um but but it's
always a possibility. Um, and like I've
experienced in my own instances, you
know, outside of Cleuly where there
there have been been investigations
um and fortunately haven't had um
anything happen. But um I I do think
there are still risks unfortunately that
that's why I think it is really positive
that we have so many more companies
having VDPs. Um I've also done a bunch
of work to get state governments um to
operate vulnerability disclosure
policies federal government. Now um
every federal agency has one. Um so
we're making a lot of good progress. Um,
and then we also have um, so Department
of Justice a couple years ago put out an
updated sentencing policy to say
essentially they wouldn't sentence
people for um, CFA violations where they
deem it good faith security research.
Um, so we're we're in a bit of a better
place. Uh but but I think still a lot of
work to be done uh to to make the this
something that um
you can you know truly go and do good
good faith security research without
having to to worry at all about uh legal
action.
>> Yeah. Yeah. That's interesting. Uh so
you're saying that you actually do think
there is more legal action brought
against people or at least threatened
legal action against people than maybe
gets publicized because I basically
never see it. I I I think so. It's it's
not like I I'm not saying it's super
common, but personally I've experienced
it. I I know other friends who have and
Right. Even if like
>> I mean you of you and some friends would
be enough to convince me that it were
common because but yeah.
>> Yeah. And even short of, you know, like
actually um getting out sentenced or uh
convicted of a crime, there there's all
sorts of kind of things that go into to
the legal cases and you know, lawyers
are notorious for not being cheap. So,
um yeah, I I think it is still a a real
consideration. Certainly, we're better
off now than we were 5 10 15 20 years
ago. But but I think um that there's um
certainly room to go.
>> Yeah. Cool. Sweet. Are you going to uh
be at Defcon?
>> I will be. Yeah. Yeah. Excited um to to
be heading back there. Uh we're going to
be sponsoring Bides this year and then
yeah, I'll be be hanging out around on
Defcon as well.
>> Nice, dude. Well, I don't typically do
this since we're uh not too late on time
at all. Do you have any like thoughts or
questions? um for me or any like kind of
just you you know we were talking before
we kind of started here uh we're both
joining like a kind of a smaller
potential contract based like red team
thing. Is there any uh red team topics
or anything that's interesting to you
that you've kind of heard about or
thought about lately?
>> I mean I'd love to to hear just like how
you've been been using AI in your own
testing. Like what what have you found
most effective? What's your kind of
day-to-day workflow?
>> Cool. Yeah, I think this episode will go
out late enough where this is fine to
talk about.
>> And if it Yeah, based on our content
calendar for the pod, it looks like
it'll go out um maybe plenty late. Yeah,
1:39. Okay, cool. Yeah, so this will
this will definitely be out by then, so
I can definitely share this. So me and
Justin and Beix have been working in
Kaido. You know, you've probably heard
of our app Shift,
>> um which was fine. it didn't do, you
know, crazy well or anything, but you
know, Kaido, um, wanted to, you know,
really take on more of like an AI
perspective. And so, um, there is a
really cool shift agents thing that
we're dropping that I will share my
screen about. Let me find a safe, uh,
project. Actually, let me just make a
new temp project. Um, but what it is is,
and Justin's been talking about this for
a while. It's called shift agents. So,
uh, I will start a new project. Create
project test
create. All right. Yeah. So, check this
out. Um, sorry for audio listeners. I'll
describe uh what I'm doing in case
you're watching, but where's the share
button? Here it is. So, share screen
window
Kaido. So, in Kaido,
um, basically there's going to be this
thing called shift agents. And what's
really cool is we have some built-in
system prompts for things like um XSS
testing, SSRF testing, passive versial
SQL injection and then you can add
custom prompts here and how these are
used by the agents is really cool. So um
let's say you send this request to uh
replay and here in replay you want to
like test for XSS and this parameter
let's just say um you know XS or
actually um input uh you know whatever.
So you can
uh oh this is switching to websockets.
Let's use a let's use a better request.
>> So um yeah we'll use this request. So
this is just some random request that
was automatically populated by Google.
>> So uh you can open this agent and then
you can choose what prompt. So if you
want to check for XSS here, you can say
like try and find XSS in the atip pram.
All right cool. So basically in shift
agents you go in you put your API key
here you validate it and then um here in
replay these agents will just like work
on your behalf. So you can say like find
an XSS a tip
for me and um it like you know there's
like the thinking blob where it's
talking about what you're talking about
and then so right now it's asking for
clarification
the first the first query par um and so
what it but what it does is it will um
modify the payload send it modify the
payload send it
>> um let's see if it's working. Yeah. So,
it modified it to this, then it sent it.
Then it's like looking and saying like,
oh, 400 bad request, so let's try
something else. So, then it's going to
send it to another payload. And so, you
can like, oh, wow, we just found a
vulnerability in Kaido. That's really
funny and really cool. This will
definitely be fixed by the time it goes
live, but that's hilarious. I'm actually
going to send that right now to the
team.
>> That is really cool and funny.
>> But anyways, you get the point, right?
And so these agents Oh my goodness
gracious. Almost.
Oh, okay. Yeah, I'm going have to kill
my Kaido. That's hilarious. Um, but
yeah, you get the point. So, that's uh
just one really cool way. I would say
you you might find this really
fascinating, especially with your AI
security research or AI safety research
>> and um specifically being in like the
contract red team stuff.
>> Um,
actually, sorry, I'm going to tag the
team. This is funny. Okay. So, um yeah,
the other way that I was using AI in the
last few days that I thought was really
cool was basically, let me stop sharing.
Um to create frames and payloads. This
is not anything new, but basically to
create frames and layered attacks for
jailbreaking other models. So, because
Grock is like kind of so easy to
jawbreak and willing to help with things
that are malicious, I've been using Croc
to basically create payloads to do
safety testing for anthropics models and
um specifically the frame for the attack
was like a fictitious website or if you
wanted a fictitious book or whatever.
Sometimes you're trying to basically get
it out of its security protections or
its guardrails. And so, you need like a
back and forth that's like make a recipe
for s like pseudafed, right? And then
it's like, oh, now let's actually make
it more dangerous and more dangerous and
more dangerous, right? Like you need
this like back and forth. And so using
models to kind of reconstruct that frame
to really save a lot of time is super
helpful.
>> Um, I've been using AI to from like not
a security perspective, but just from a
building perspective to build like
little side projects. Like one of my,
you know, ones I'm most excited about is
basically a soccer ranking thing for my
good buddy who's like a high school
soccer coach. And so like I'm really
excited for it to like rank, you know,
like local high school teams with like
ELO and everything to kind of like
predict which team's better and how
they're doing and all that. So I think
that's really cool. Um
>> and then I'm trying to think if there's
anything else from like a security
perspective that I'm doing.
>> Um I where I'm a adviser for Ethi. I
consult them on their hackbot they're
building and I'm adviser for Splick. So
I consult them on like their AI safety
stuff. And so, you know, getting to see
kind of the hackbot side of things and
then the safety testing side of things
like pretty fascinating and cool. But
>> yeah. Yeah, it's awesome. Yeah. And
super cool to see the the Kaido um
Asgent. Yeah, definitely feels like
where the the future is going is like
that. Yeah, I don't know if we're at a
fully autonomous stage, but but
certainly similar to, you know, how
Yeah, you can now go and code much
faster. It feels like that it is just
going to come to to security to to bug
bounties and make everything work a
whole lot faster.
>> Yeah, I don't think that it's going to
be worth it to do what I just showed you
on like every parameter on every tab,
right? Like go find XSS. But what I do
think will be really valuable is it's
like,
>> hey, I found this parameter and I know
it does something weird here and I need
to find like a bypass. Can you just try
like every possible unic code
normalization pair? can you try every
special character in this in this thing
and just like tell me which one's
interesting and just like set it off to
running. I think that is where it will
really pay off um in the short term
>> and then you know maybe long term we'll
get something more like an autonomous
hackbot. Um
>> y
>> but yeah and one thing that I think is
really cool about Kaido actually this
will be coming out sometime in a month
or two. So this is like something that's
worth thinking about. I'm sure you saw
um OpenAI just released their new agent
thing. I actually just got access today.
I haven't played with it yet, but that
along with all these other companies are
basically building browser use.
>> Yep.
>> And what's really neat about Kaido,
which is not true for Burp, is that it
is a website, right? But it's like
basically a little web server. And so
you can you can just tell these agents
like especially if they're like local
ones. So um if you're you know what's
the new one? It's um perplexity comet or
the dia browser. like if you're using
browser use stuff like that and these
models are going to keep getting better
at browser use um to use your you know
use your own computer or whatever or set
up something you can have Kaido just
like boot it up and these models can
actually browse around in Kaido to do
things. So you could you know have it
actually take actions in Kaido to help
you hack or to like set up some sort of
hacking thing or whatever. So I think
that's pretty cool and a reason why I'm
excited to be an adviser for Kaido uh
because I do think them being
browserbased is actually going to be a
huge key differentiator. So
>> yeah. Yeah, it's super exciting.
>> Cool, dude. Well, we really appreciate
you coming on the pod and I look forward
to seeing you at Defcon and for anyone
listening to this. Um uh heed Jack's
words on what you should and shouldn't
hack and go uh go promote your your
local governments, but also your
company's uh VDP or VRP program if they
don't have one. So,
>> cheers.
>> Exactly. Well, yeah. Thank you.
>> Oh, actually, where can people find you,
Jack?
>> Yeah. Where can people find you?
>> Awesome. Yeah, I'm on, you know,
Twitter, Jackh Cable, LinkedIn as well.
Um, so and yeah, I'll be around Defcon
as well.
>> Awesome. Thanks. See you.
>> Great. Peace.
>> Thank you.
>> And that's a wrap on this episode of
Critical Thinking. Thanks so much for
watching to the end, y'all. If you want
more critical thinking content, uh, or
if you want to support the show, head
over to ctbb.show/isord.
You can hop in the community. There's
lots of great highlevel hacking
discussion happening there on top of
master classes, hackalongs, exclusive
content, and a full-time hunters guild
if you're a full-time hunter. It's a
great time, trust me. All right, I'll
see you there.
[Music]